<?xml version="1.0"?>
<resources>
  <resource>
    <h3 id="chicagodefender">About the Chicago Defender</h3>
    <p><span class="snippet">Founded by Robert S. Abbott in 1905, the Chicago
Defender is one of America's longest-running African American
newspapers.</span> The Defender is best known for having spurred the Great
Migration of African Americans from the southern United States to the nation's
urban centers in the north--especially Chicago--during the first decades of the
20th century. The Defender also paved the way for the modernization of the
Black press, given its capital resources; advanced printing technologies;
national and international distribution networks; and multi-cultural,
transnational readership.</p>

    <p>The paper's signal collection is its photograph archives, which contain
nearly 100,000 items. A limited number of vintage images dates back as early as
the 1930-40s, but the strength of the collection lies in photographs from the
1960s-1990s.</p>

    <p>Topically, the archives are particularly strong in the fields of Black
business, politics (local, state, national, and international), the Civil
Rights Movement, entertainment, celebrities, leisure culture, sports, community
organizations, and community activism.</p>

    <p>For information about the Chicago Defender, visit <a
href="http://www.chicagodefender.com/">chicagodefender.com</a> or email <a
href="mailto:copyright@chicagodefender.com">copyright@chicagodefender.com</a>.</p>
</resource>
  <resource>
    <h3 id="dusable">About the DuSable Museum of African American History</h3>
    <p><span class="snippet">Founded in 1961 and the oldest institution of its
kind in the U.S., the DuSable Museum of African American History mounts
exhibits that interpret African American and African history for the general
public.</span></p>

    <p>The exhibition holdings range from paintings by master African American
artists, a collection of over 2,000 African artifacts and a range of objects
from the early 1800's to the present. There is an extensive photographic
collection as well as costumes, works on paper, and sculpture.</p>

    <p>The Archives/Research Collection contains the personal papers of notable
African Americans, rare books, periodicals, manuscripts, political ephemera,
oral histories, film, video and communications equipment documenting African
and African American leadership, businesses, organizations and institutions.
The scope of the collections ranges from the southside of Chicago to national
and international history, art and culture.</p>

    <p>For information about the DuSable Museum of African American History, visit <a href="http://www.dusablemuseum.org/">dusablemuseum.org</a> or email <a href="mailto:mts@dusablemuseum.org">mts@dusablemuseum.org</a>.</p>
  </resource>
  <resource>
    <h3 id="sscac">About the South Side Community Art Center</h3>
    <p><span class="snippet">The South Side Community Art Center is the oldest
African American Art Center in existence. It has held classes in drawing,
painting, sculpture, printmaking, photography and crafts, even going beyond the
visual arts and offered literary and performing arts programs as well.</span>
The Center has an impressive collection of works by African-American artists
like Charles White, Henry Avery, Archibald Motley, Jr. and Marian Perkins.</p>

    <p>Although during the 1930's the WPA provided funds to hire staff and
faculty and to remodel the South Side Community Art Center's building, the
community had to pay for the lease and purchase of the building, for utilities,
and for art supplies. At the time of Depression this was especially difficult
for poor communities.</p>

    <p>The original fundraising efforts involved three years of activity,
including theater performances, card parties, a 'Mile of Dimes' street-corner
campaign, lectures and exhibitions held in churches, community centers, schools
and clubhouses. The most successful event was the Artists' and Models' Ball
held on October 23, 1939 at the Savoy Ballroom. This single event raised the
funds to acquire the building for the future Center.</p>

    <p>The South Side Community Art Center continues to act as a resource for
the arts community locally and abroad. It takes pride in its past and present
contributions to the development and showcasing of emerging and established
artists.</p>

    <p>For information about the South Side Community Art Center, <a
href="http://www.southsidecommunityartcenter.com/">visit their website</a>.</p>
</resource>

  <resource>
    <h3 id="chicagojazzarchive">Chicago Jazz Archive</h3>

    <p><span class="snippet">The Chicago Jazz Archive was founded in 1976 to
preserve materials on the birth and early growth of Chicago jazz.</span> Over
time, due in part to a relationship with the Jazz Institute of Chicago, the
collections have grown to span more than eight decades of Chicago and general
jazz history. The collections include recordings, publications, photographs,
articles, posters, programs, ticket stubs, and other ephemera of musicians,
clubs, record companies, and jazz organizations. In 2007-2008, the collections
of the Chicago Jazz Archive were transferred to the Special Collections
Research Center.  Chicago Jazz Archive manuscript and archival collections were
part of the Uncovering New Chicago Archives Project (UNCAP), a three-year initiative
funded by the Andrew W.  Mellon Foundation. The University of Chicago Library
provides access to the Chicago Jazz Archive through the Hanna Holborn Gray
Special Collections Research Center.</p>
  </resource>

</resources>
